<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

<chapter id="chap-Publican-Introduction">
	<title>Introduction</title>
	<para>
		Publican is a tool for publishing material authored in DocBook XML. This guide explains how to  to create and build books and articles using publican. It is not a DocBook XML tutorial and concentrates solely on using the publican tools. See <ulink url="http://docbook.org/tdg/en/html/docbook.html">docbook.org</ulink> for information about DocBook XML.
	</para>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Design</title>
		<para>
			Publican is a publication system, not just a DocBook processing tool. As well as ensuring your DocBook XML is valid, publican works to ensure your XML is up to publishable standard.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<para>
		The Branding functionality allows you to create your own presentation rules and look, over-riding many parts of the default style to meet your publishing needs. Choices executed in code, however, are not changeable.
	</para>

	<para>
		Entities, for example, can be validly defined in any XML file. However, to ensure the DTD declaration is present, valid and standardized, Publican rewrites the declaration in every XML file before it builds a book or article. Consequently, all entities declared in all XML files are lost. Publican, therefore, requires you define Entities in the <filename><replaceable>Book_Name</replaceable>.ent</filename> file (see <xref linkend="sect-Publican-Files_in_the_Book_directory-Book_Name.ent" />).
	</para>
	<para>
		As publishing workflows grow, unrestrained Entity definition leads to Entity duplication and other practices that cause maintenance difficulties. Consolidating Entity definitions in a single, predictable place alleviates these maintenance issues and helps the automation of the build process stay robust.
	</para>
	<para>
		If there is sufficient demand to add conditions or over-ride this and other choices designed to improve and maintain the published standard of material, we will consider requests to add such functionality.
	</para>

</chapter>
