<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

<chapter id="chap-Publican-Using_Sets">
	<title>Using Sets</title>
	<para>
		A set is a book that contains a collection of other books. The <citetitle>Services Plan</citetitle> for example is a book comprised of many other books such as the <citetitle>Developer Guide</citetitle>, <citetitle>Engineering Content Services Guide</citetitle> and the <citetitle>Engineering Operations Guide</citetitle>, to name just a few. The <command>create_book</command> command creates sets by setting the <parameter>type</parameter> parameter to Set.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Publican-Using_Sets-Creating_a_Set">
		<title>Creating a Set</title>
		<para>
			The procedure that follows will guide you through the process of creating a set named <citetitle>My Set</citetitle> containing <citetitle>Book A</citetitle>, <citetitle>Book B</citetitle> and <citetitle>Book C</citetitle>.
		</para>
		<important>
			<para>
				This process assumes that <citetitle>Book A</citetitle>, <citetitle>Book B</citetitle> and <citetitle>Book C</citetitle> already exists and are avaialable in your <package>SVN</package> repository. Currently <package>publican</package> only supports <package>SVN</package>.
			</para>
		</important>
		<procedure id="proc-Publican-Creating_a_Set-Creating_a_Set">
			<title>Creating a Set</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Run the following command in a shell to create a set named <literal>My_Set</literal> branded in the Red Hat style.
				</para>
<programlisting>
create_book --type=Set --name=My_Set --brand=RedHat
</programlisting>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Edit the <filename>Makefile</filename> and change the following 2 lines from:
				</para>
<programlisting>
#BOOKS		= My_Other_Book His_Book Her_Book Their_Book
#SET_REPO	= http://svn.repo.com/repos/project
</programlisting>
				<para>
					to :
				</para>
<programlisting>
BOOKS 		= Book_A Book_B Book_C
SET_REPO	= <replaceable>http://PATH-TO-YOUR-SVN-REPOSITORY</replaceable>
</programlisting>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Open the <filename>My_Set.xml</filename> file in an editor add one <sgmltag>xi:include</sgmltag> to the primary xml files from each book. The <filename>My_Set.xml</filename> file should look similar to this:
				</para>
<programlisting>
<xi:include parse="text" href="extras/Set_Name.xmlt" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"></xi:include>
</programlisting>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Test your book set by running the <command>make test-en-US</command> command.
				</para>
				<important>
					<para>
						When building a set, the <command>make clean_ids</command> command will be run over each book because of the constraint that ID&#39;s must be unique across all books. Be careful of creating IDs that rely on content that may not be avaialable when building books independently of the set.
					</para>
				</important>
			</step>
		</procedure>

	</section>

</chapter>

