<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Users_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section conformance="140" id="sect-Users_Guide-Pre_release_software_and_draft_documentation">
	<title>Pre-release software and draft documentation</title>
	 <para>
		Completed documentation for pre-release software is not the same thing as draft documentation.
	</para>
	 <para>
		Drafts are unfinished versions of a book or article, and their unfinished state is unrelated to the status of the software they document.
	</para>
	 <para>
		In both circumstances, however, it is important to make the status of the software, documentation or both clear to users, developers, readers and reviewers.
	</para>
	 <section conformance="141" id="sect-Users_Guide-Pre_release_software_and_draft_documentation-Denoting_pre_release_software">
		<title>Denoting pre-release software</title>
		 <para>
			Documentation for pre-release software, especially pre-release software being distributed to testers, customers and partners, should carry a clear mark denoting the beta-status of the software.
		</para>
		 <para>
			To create that mark do the following:
		</para>
		 <procedure>
			<step>
				<para>
					Add the software's pre-release version number, or equivalent state information, to the <sgmltag>&lt;subtitle&gt;</sgmltag> tag in your <filename>Book_Info.xml</filename> file. Place this additional text in <sgmltag>&lt;remark&gt;</sgmltag> tags. For example:
				</para>
				 
<programlisting language="XML">&lt;subtitle&gt;Using Red Hat Enterprise Warp Drive&lt;remark&gt; Version 1.1, Beta 2&lt;/remark&gt;&lt;/subtitle&gt;

</programlisting>

			</step>
			 <step>
				<para>
					add <varname>show_remarks</varname> to the <filename>publican.cfg</filename> file and set it to '1':
				</para>
				 
<programlisting>show_remarks: 1

</programlisting>

			</step>

		</procedure>
		
		 <para>
			When you build your book with this <sgmltag>&lt;remark&gt;</sgmltag> tag and the <varname>show_remarks</varname> setting in place, the pre-release nature of the software is displayed clearly and unmistakably. PDF builds display the remark on their cover and title pages. HTML builds (both single-page HTML and multiple-page HTML) display the remark near the beginning of <filename>index.html</filename>.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Because this approach makes no changes to the information in <filename>Book_Info.xml</filename> used to generate RPMs, it also ensures there is no ambiguity in the RPM subsystem's operation.
		</para>
		 <important>
			<title>Important</title>
			 <para>
				It is the writer's responsibility to remove the <sgmltag>&lt;remark&gt;</sgmltag> tag and its contents and remove or turn off <varname>show_remarks</varname> when documentation is updated for use with the release version of the software.
			</para>

		</important>

	</section>
	
	 <section conformance="142" id="sect-Users_Guide-Pre_release_software_and_draft_documentation-Denoting_draft_documentation">
		<title>Denoting draft documentation</title>
		 <para>
			Unfinished documentation made available to others for review should be labeled clearly as such.
		</para>
		 <procedure>
			<step>
				<para>
					To add the draft watermark to your documentation add the <userinput>status="draft"</userinput> attribute to the <sgmltag>&lt;article&gt;</sgmltag>, <sgmltag>&lt;book&gt;</sgmltag> or <sgmltag>&lt;set&gt;</sgmltag> tag in your document's root node. For example:
				</para>
				 
<programlisting language="XML">&lt;book status="draft"&gt;

</programlisting>

			</step>

		</procedure>
		
		 <para>
			By default, your root node is the <sgmltag>&lt;book&gt;</sgmltag> tag in your <filename><replaceable>Doc_Name</replaceable>.xml</filename> file.
		</para>
		 <para>
			If you are working on an article or set, the root node is the <sgmltag>&lt;article&gt;</sgmltag> or <sgmltag>&lt;set&gt;</sgmltag> tag in <filename><replaceable>Doc_Name</replaceable>.xml</filename>.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Adding the <userinput>status="draft"</userinput> attribute causes each page of the document to show the draft watermark. This is by design.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Even if you change only a portion of a work before sending it out for review, marking every page as draft will encourage reviewers to report errors or typos they spot in passing. It will also ensure non-reviewers who encounter the work do not mistake a draft for a finished version.
		</para>

	</section>
	
	 <section conformance="143" id="sect-Users_Guide-Pre_release_software_and_draft_documentation-Denoting_draft_documentation_of_pre_release_software">
		<title>Denoting draft documentation of pre-release software</title>
		 <para>
			To denote unfinished documentation of pre-release software properly, do both previously noted procedures.
		</para>

	</section>
	

</section>
