<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Users_Guide.ent">
]>
		 <section conformance="186" id="sect-Users_Guide-Linux_operating_systems-Debian">
			<title>Debian</title>
			<para>
				This procedure will install the <application>publican</application> version that is in your default Debian repository. It will also install a large number of packages that <application>publican</application> depends on, like Java, XML and image processing libraries and many ancillary Perl modules.
			</para>

			 <procedure>
				<step>
					<para>
						Open a terminal.
					</para>

				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Change to the root user: <command> su - </command>
					</para>
				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Run the following command to install the <package>publican</package> package:
					</para>
					
					<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>apt-get install publican</command>
					</screen>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Run the following command to determine what version of <package>publican</package> is installed:
					</para>
					
					<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>publican -v</command>
					version=2.8
					</screen>

				</step>
			</procedure>

			 <important>
				<title> Important — Installing more recent packages using Apt-Pinning</title>
				 <para>
					If you need a more recent release of <package>publican</package> than installed by the procedure above, you can query if there other versions available: <ulink url="http://packages.Debian.org/search?keywords=publican+searchon=names+suite=allsection=all" />.
				</para>
				<para>
					To date, there has not been any backport (<ulink url="http://backports.Debian.org/Instructions/" />) available for <application>publican</application>, so we need to use Apt Pinning <ulink url="https://wiki.Debian.org/AptPreferences" />
				</para>
				<para>
					Alternatively, you could run Debian testing or unstable in a virtual machine, chroot or linux container. 
				</para>
				<para>
**************** docker image anyone?***************
				</para>

			</important>
			<para>
				Assuming there is a more recent version of <application>publican</application> available in the testing repository, and that you are running the current stable, then you can upgrade by:
			</para>

			 <procedure>
				<step>
					<para>
						Open a terminal.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Change to the root user: <command> su - </command>
					</para>
				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Open your <filename>/etc/apt/sources.list</filename> file in a text editor. For example, to edit the file in <application>gedit</application> run:
					</para>
					 
<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>gedit /etc/apt/sources.list</command>
</screen>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Add the following line to the end of the file:
					</para>
					 
<programlisting>
#### testing  #########
deb http://ftp.us.Debian.org/Debian testing main contrib non-free
</programlisting>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Save the file and close the text editor.
					</para>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Open (or create) your <filename>/etc/apt/preferences</filename> file in a text editor. For example, to edit the file in <application>gedit</application> run:
					</para>
					 
<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>gedit /etc/apt/preferences</command>
</screen>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Add the following line to the end of the file:
					</para>
					 
<programlisting>
Package: *
Pin: release a=stable
Pin-Priority: 900

Package: *
Pin: release a=testing
Pin-Priority: 400

Package: *
Pin: release o=Debian
Pin-Priority: -10

</programlisting>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Save the file and close the text editor.
					</para>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Run the following command to update the list of packages available to your computer:
					</para>
					 
<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>apt-get update</command>
</screen>

				</step>
				 <step>
					<para>
						Run the following command to try to install the testing version of <package>publican</package> package, and any updated dependancies:
					</para>
					 
<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>apt-get -t testing install publican</command>
</screen>

				</step>
			</procedure>
			<para>
				Because Apt Pinning mixes 2 different debian streams in an un-tested way, incompatibilities may happen. For example, you may get a warning like:

				<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>publican</command>
				Warning: program compiled against libxml 209 using older 208
				Warning: XML::LibXML compiled against libxml2 20901, but runtime libxml2 is older 20800
				Warning: program compiled against libxml 209 using older 208
				Warning: XML::LibXSLT compiled against libxslt 10128, but runtime libxslt is older 10126
				Can't open publican: No such file or directory at /usr/bin/publican line 430.
				</screen>
				Which indicates that you might need to upgrade libxml2 and libxslt to the testing repository version too. This can be done by
			</para>

			<procedure>
				<step>
					<para>
						searching to find the likely library:
<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>apt-get search libxslt</command>
gambas3-gb-xml-xslt - Gambas XSLT component
libidzebra-2.0-mod-alvis - IDZebra filter alvis (XSLT filter for XML)
libidzebra-2.0-mod-dom - IDZebra filter 'dom' (XML DOM internal document model with XSLT)
libical-parser-html-perl - generates HTML calendars from iCalendars
libxsltc-java - XSL Transformations (XSLT) compiler from Xalan-Java
libxml-filter-xslt-perl - Perl module for XSLT as a SAX Filter
libxml-libxslt-perl - Perl interface to the GNOME libxslt library
libxslt1-dbg - XSLT 1.0 processing library - debugging symbols
libxslt1-dev - XSLT 1.0 processing library - development kit
libxslt1.1 - XSLT 1.0 processing library - runtime library
python-libxslt1 - Python bindings for libxslt1
python-libxslt1-dbg - Python bindings for libxslt1 (debug extension)
python-lxml - pythonic binding for the libxml2 and libxslt libraries
python-lxml-dbg - pythonic binding for the libxml2 and libxslt libraries (debug extension)
python-lxml-doc - pythonic binding for the libxml2 and libxslt libraries (documentation)
python3-lxml - pythonic binding for the libxml2 and libxslt libraries
python3-lxml-dbg - pythonic binding for the libxml2 and libxslt libraries (debug extension)
php5-xsl - XSL module for php5
libsp-gxmlcpp-dev - S+P C++ wrapper for Gnome libxml2/libxslt
libsp-gxmlcpp1 - S+P C++ wrapper for Gnome libxml2/libxslt
swfmill - xml2swf and swf2xml processor
libxslthl-java - XSLT syntax highlighting
</screen>
(and the same again for libxml2)
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
And then upgrading those packages to testing.
<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>apt-get -t testing upgrade libxml2 libxslt1.1</command>
</screen>
					</para>
				</step>
			</procedure>

		</section>
