<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE appendix PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<appendix id="appe-Users_Guide-Makefile_Parameters">
	<title>Makefile Parameters</title>
	<para>
		Every Book, Article or Book Set has a Makefile in its root directory. Parameters that can be set in a Book&#39;s Makefile are:
	</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BOOKS</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					This defines the Books a Set contains. It is only useful for Book Sets.
				</para>
				<para>
					Default value: Undefined.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BRAND</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					This parameter tells Publican which Brand to apply to a book&#39;s html and pdf output. Its default value is: common.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BREW_DIST</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					BREW_DIST sets the Brew tag for desktop RPMs. Default: dist-5E-qu-candidate.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>CHUNK_FIRST</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Controls chunking of first sections. 0 or 1. Default: 0.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>CHUNK_SECTION_DEPTH</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Override the max section depth to chunk to. Default: 4.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>COMMON_CONFIG</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Sets the path to Publican&#39;s configuration and common files, including Brand files. Default: <filename>/usr/share/publican</filename>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>CONFIDENTIAL</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The default value 0 is not confidential. To set a book to confidential, change this to 1.
				</para>
				<para>
					Setting this parameter to 1 places a large <emphasis>Confidential</emphasis> footer on each page.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>DEFAULT_LANGS</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Languages that should be included in xi:include even if the translation is not complete. Used in update_includes. Default: Undefined.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>DESKTOP</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use the desktop CSS (1) or not (0). Default: 0
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>DOC_TYPE</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Sets the sort of publication being produced: Book, Article or Set. Default value is Book. This paremeter has no relationship to the DOCTYPE declaration in a publication&#39;s XML files.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>DOC_URL</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Sets the URL used for the link in the right-hand header of every html page. Also sets the URL entry in a publication&#39;s RPM spec file. Default: https://fedorahosted.org/publican
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>DT_OBSOLETES</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					A comma separated list of desk top packages the package should obsolete. Default: undefined.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>EMBEDTOC</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Embed the web navigation TOC in the html. 0 or 1. Default: 0.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>GENERATE_SECTION_TOC_LEVEL</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Include a Table of Contents at the given section level. Valid values: 0 5. Default: 0.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>IGNORED_TRANSLATIONS</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When building, replace any languages in this list with the source langauge text. This allows you to work on translations without shipping incomplete translations. Default: Undefined.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>OTHER_LANGS</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Space separated list of language locales. Default: Undefined.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>PRODUCT</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The product this book is associated with. Default: Documentation.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>PROD_URL</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Sets the URL used for the link in the left-hand header of every html page. Default: https://fedorahosted.org/publican
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>SHOW_REMARKS</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Display contents of remark tags in output? Two possible values: 0 (off) or 1 (on). Off by default.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>TOC_SECTION_DEPTH</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					How many section levels should be included in the main Table of Contents. Default: 2.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>WEB_BREW_DIST</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					WEB_BREW_DIST sets the Brew tag for web RPMs. Default: docs-5E.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>WEB_OBSOLETES</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					A comma separated list of web site packages the web package should obsolete. Default: Undefined.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>XML_LANG</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Language of a publication&#39;s source xml. Default: en-US (US English).
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>USE_SAXON</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use saxon for xslt. Two possible values: 0 (off) or 1 (on). On by default.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>USE_XALAN</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Test xalan for xslt. 0 or 1. Default: 0.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</appendix>

