<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Users_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section conformance="228" id="sect-Users_Guide-Website-homepage-rpm">
	<title>Creating, installing, and updating the home page</title>
	<para>
		The <application>Publican</application>-generated home page is the localizable page to which visitors are directed by the site JavaScript and which provides the style for the website structure. The home page is structured as a DocBook <sgmltag>&lt;article&gt;</sgmltag> with an extra <parameter>web_type:&nbsp;home</parameter> parameter in its <filename>publican.cfg</filename> file. In its structure and its presentation, the home page is the same as any other article that you produce with <application>Publican</application> and is packaged the same way.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<step>
			<para>
				On a workstation, create a home page using the procedure described in <xref linkend="sect-Users_Guide-Website-homepage-manual" />.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the directory in which you created the home page, run: 
			</para>
<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <command>publican package --binary</command></screen>
			<para>
				<application>Publican</application> builds an RPM package and places it in the <filename>/tmp/rpms/noarch/</filename> directory of the home page. By default, <application>Publican</application> builds the RPM package for the operating system within which you are running <application>Publican</application>. To build an RPM package to install on a server that runs a different operating system, set the <parameter>os_ver</parameter> parameter in the home page's <filename>publican.cfg</filename> file. 
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Either upload the home page package to the webserver and install it with the <command>rpm -i</command> or <command>yum localinstall</command> command, or place the package in a repository and configure the webserver to install from that repository when you run <command>yum install</command>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		To update the home page, build a new package with a higher <sgmltag>&lt;edition&gt;</sgmltag> number or <sgmltag>&lt;pubsnumber&gt;</sgmltag> in the  <filename>Article_Info.xml</filename>. <application>Publican</application> uses these values to set the version and release numbers for the RPM package. When you install this package on your webserver, <application>yum</application> can replace the old version with the new when you run <command>yum localinstall</command> for a local package, or <command>yum update</command> for a package fetched from a repository.
	</para>
</section>
